<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-08-09T16:39:35-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">M3J</title><subtitle>M3J is a free virtual math modeling challenge for fifth to ninth graders!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">What are workshops?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/faqs/question-two" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What are workshops?" /><published>2019-12-05T07:44:38-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-07T20:33:05-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/faqs/question-two</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/faqs/question-two"></content><author><name></name></author><category term="faqs" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Changing Odin’s Base Content</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/customizing-odin/changing-odin-base-content" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Changing Odin’s Base Content" /><published>2019-11-05T07:44:38-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-07T20:33:05-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/customizing-odin/changing-odin-base-content</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/customizing-odin/changing-odin-base-content">&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is a stub, more info coming soon. Some sections should be cleaned up.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can change virtually all of Odin’s content from the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt; file. There are three things you cannot change from here, which need to be changed elsewhere - &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;colors&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;fonts&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;categories&lt;/a&gt;. Everything else is edited from this file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;base-content&quot;&gt;Base Content&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the top of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt; you’ll find a number of base settings you should change. These include your site title and description, as well as your brand logo and name. It also includes options to change the home page header and subheader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;navigation-links&quot;&gt;Navigation Links&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of the box, Odin supports 3 custom navigation links + a ‘return home’ button. Each link supports a name and a link. If you want to disable a link, just add &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; to both options for that link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The navigation button can be edited by changing the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nav_button&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nav_button_link&lt;/code&gt; options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;more-help-section&quot;&gt;More Help Section&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more help section shows up under your list of categories on your homepage, as well as under each article. This section supports 0, 1 or 2 content blocks, which can be edited from the # More Help section of the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt; file. These sections are a great way to add links to your email, twitter, or other methods for users to reach you for support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;help_one_title&lt;/strong&gt; - the header title for this section&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;help_one_content&lt;/strong&gt; - the extended text for this help section. Works best if under 200 characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;help_one_button&lt;/strong&gt; - the text to show for the link in this help section&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;help_one_link&lt;/strong&gt; - where the help section button should take users&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;social-links&quot;&gt;Social Links&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The social links section defines which social links show in the footer. By default Odin supports Instagram, Twitter, Facebook, LinkedIn, Email, and Github. Simply add the relevant social item to the right section, or add &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#&lt;/code&gt; if you don’t want that social item to show in the footer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After making any changes to the above, run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt; to see the changes locally. If you’re satisfied with your changes, run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll build&lt;/code&gt; and then push your changes to your repo.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mac Reddin</name></author><category term="customizing-odin" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Changing Odin Colors</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/customizing-odin/changing-odin-colors" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Changing Odin Colors" /><published>2019-11-05T07:44:38-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-07T20:33:05-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/customizing-odin/changing-odin-colors</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/customizing-odin/changing-odin-colors">&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article is a stub, more info coming soon. Colors in Odin are currently a bit messy and need to be cleaned up&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To change the colors used in Odin, first navigate to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_scss/_variables.scss&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This file contains all of the colors used in Odin. The primary colors you should be concerned about changing are listed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$primary-color&lt;/strong&gt; - the main brand color used in Odin. This is used in places such as header background and link colors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$highlight-color&lt;/strong&gt; - primarily used for link hover states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After editing any colors, run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt; to see the changes locally. If you’re satisfied with your changes, run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll build&lt;/code&gt; and then push your changes to your repo.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mac Reddin</name></author><category term="customizing-odin" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Changing Odin Fonts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/customizing-odin/changing-odin-fonts" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Changing Odin Fonts" /><published>2019-11-05T07:44:38-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-07T20:33:05-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/customizing-odin/changing-odin-fonts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/customizing-odin/changing-odin-fonts">&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default Odin uses two Google Fonts, Muli and Poppins. To change these font choices, first navigate to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_scss/_variables&lt;/code&gt; and find the Google Font import on line 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Replace this import with the Google Font(s) of your choice and then find the Fonts section of the variable file (starts on line 50). Make sure to update these to use your chosen fonts, primarily &lt;strong&gt;$base-font-family&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;$header-font-family&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After editing your fonts, run jekyll serve to see the changes locally. If you’re satisfied with your changes, run jekyll build and then push your changes to your repo.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mac Reddin</name></author><category term="customizing-odin" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is math modeling?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/faqs/question-one" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is math modeling?" /><published>2019-11-05T07:44:38-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-07T20:33:05-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/faqs/question-one</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/faqs/question-one"></content><author><name></name></author><category term="faqs" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Additional Documents</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/resources/additional-documents" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Additional Documents" /><published>2019-11-05T07:44:38-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-07T20:33:05-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/resources/additional-documents</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/resources/additional-documents">&lt;p&gt;For guidance on specific tools, like Python or LaTeX, check &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;! We will also be routinely updating our YouTube channel &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3ge6-bfAyjfRiXGL7no1vw&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; with any video resources we have.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="resources" /><summary type="html">For guidance on specific tools, like Python or LaTeX, check here! We will also be routinely updating our YouTube channel here with any video resources we have.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Judges Comments</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/resources/judges-comments" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Judges Comments" /><published>2019-11-05T07:44:38-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-07T20:33:05-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/resources/judges-comments</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/resources/judges-comments">&lt;p&gt;M&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;J judges will grade each paper and provide feedback to each team on their designated rubric. Check out how our sample paper was graded on Google Docs &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1zNK_fMlLQLN0hPt7fXZE9HTNDQeJkcFiGRlD7KQFPug/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; by some of our event runners!
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="resources" /><summary type="html">M3J judges will grade each paper and provide feedback to each team on their designated rubric. Check out how our sample paper was graded on Google Docs here by some of our event runners!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rubric</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/resources/rubric" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rubric" /><published>2019-11-05T07:44:38-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-07T20:33:05-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/resources/rubric</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/resources/rubric">&lt;p&gt;M&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;J judges will be graded based on a standard rubric. While your team does not have to look at the rubric, it can be a great reference for how you can improve your paper! For any questions or clarifications, the M3J event runners are here to help! View the rubric we'll use in the event on Google Spreadsheets &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/10FZvLP1zLikN8odDJ4_VITP2hjQ1oRAqEKAQE4SXEfk/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="resources" /><summary type="html">M3J judges will be graded based on a standard rubric. While your team does not have to look at the rubric, it can be a great reference for how you can improve your paper! For any questions or clarifications, the M3J event runners are here to help! View the rubric we'll use in the event on Google Spreadsheets here.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sample Papers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/resources/sample-papers" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sample Papers" /><published>2019-11-05T07:44:38-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-07T20:33:05-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/resources/sample-papers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/resources/sample-papers">&lt;p&gt;Not sure where to start? We got your back! See below for an example of a math modeling paper (developed by yours truly) and a template for your team to get started.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't worry if you don't have a plan! The M&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;J modelers and mentors are always here to help if you ask! Email us at any time, or feel free to use Discord or Zoom to contact us during the event.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Sample Prompt&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attached is the prompt M&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;J some problem writers answered in a sample paper at Mass Academy. This is not the official 2021 Math Jam prompt. For this year's prompts for the Junior and Senior division, check out the 2021 Math Modeling page.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most drivers have a &quot;usual&quot; region in which they do most of their driving. However, gas prices may vary widely so that gas may be substantially cheaper somewhere other than within that usual region. Would it be more economical to go to a station outside the usual region to buy gas? Thus, the general question we wish to address is, &quot;How might we determine which gas station is the most cost-efficient?&quot;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You drive to school every day. On the route you take from home to school, there are several gas stations. Unfortunately, the prices on your route are always high. A friend tells you she buys her gas at a station several miles off your normal route where the prices are cheaper. A diagram of the gas stations nearby and their prices are shown below:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/problem.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image of the problem&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which gas station would be the most economical for you to go to?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Sample Paper&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure what to write in your paper? No worries! Some Mass Academy students answered a sample prompt in this math modeling report. Feel free to use this as a starting point or template for your own work to guide you in the right direction! Heads up though, this is not the most accurate, well written, or creative solution out there! This is just here as an example for how a math modeling paper and judging would look like. I'm sure you could think of several better solutions to this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that you cannot copy and paste any content from this paper into your own. View the paper on Google Docs &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1Yl5EOtGty0q3_kwc5jq07Uba_-hRUJ1vVU1afy07lTQ/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Paper Template&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure where to start with your paper? No worries! Event runners have organized this example for what sections your paper can include. Please note that you do not have to cite this template in your citations, but you should remove each section description before submitting your paper. If you decide not to use this template, please make sure you include all of the sections outlined in the template in your own paper. View the paper on Google Docs &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1p74TIbV6MqcdQUeSTwvMDwFyZmwjSmi5tMBTYLKVU4w/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="resources" /><summary type="html">Not sure where to start? We got your back! See below for an example of a math modeling paper (developed by yours truly) and a template for your team to get started. Don't worry if you don't have a plan! The M3J modelers and mentors are always here to help if you ask! Email us at any time, or feel free to use Discord or Zoom to contact us during the event. Sample Prompt Attached is the prompt M3J some problem writers answered in a sample paper at Mass Academy. This is not the official 2021 Math Jam prompt. For this year's prompts for the Junior and Senior division, check out the 2021 Math Modeling page. Most drivers have a &quot;usual&quot; region in which they do most of their driving. However, gas prices may vary widely so that gas may be substantially cheaper somewhere other than within that usual region. Would it be more economical to go to a station outside the usual region to buy gas? Thus, the general question we wish to address is, &quot;How might we determine which gas station is the most cost-efficient?&quot; You drive to school every day. On the route you take from home to school, there are several gas stations. Unfortunately, the prices on your route are always high. A friend tells you she buys her gas at a station several miles off your normal route where the prices are cheaper. A diagram of the gas stations nearby and their prices are shown below: Which gas station would be the most economical for you to go to? Sample Paper Not sure what to write in your paper? No worries! Some Mass Academy students answered a sample prompt in this math modeling report. Feel free to use this as a starting point or template for your own work to guide you in the right direction! Heads up though, this is not the most accurate, well written, or creative solution out there! This is just here as an example for how a math modeling paper and judging would look like. I'm sure you could think of several better solutions to this problem. Please note that you cannot copy and paste any content from this paper into your own. View the paper on Google Docs here. Paper Template Not sure where to start with your paper? No worries! Event runners have organized this example for what sections your paper can include. Please note that you do not have to cite this template in your citations, but you should remove each section description before submitting your paper. If you decide not to use this template, please make sure you include all of the sections outlined in the template in your own paper. View the paper on Google Docs here.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Academic Honesty</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/academic-honesty" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Academic Honesty" /><published>2019-11-05T07:44:38-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-07T20:33:05-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/academic-honesty</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/academic-honesty">&lt;p&gt;Academic honesty is the principle of being honest in all the work you do. In the context of M&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;J, an academically honest team creates their own model and reports it without cheating or presenting the work of others as their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If academic dishonesty is detected, teams will be given a 2-hour window to correct their mistake. Otherwise, the M3J Team will disqualify the paper to ensure a fair playing field for everyone.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research is encouraged and an important part of making a good model. If you ever quote, paraphrase, use an image or graph that you did not make, or reference facts that you found while researching, you MUST cite your sources. You cannot take credit for work that is not yours. For example, below is a acceptable citation for this webpage that was generated through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.easybib.com/&quot;&gt;Easybib&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team, MMMJ. &quot;MMMJ Website.&quot; M&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;J, 1 Jan. 2021, mmmjam.github.io/. 
&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://mmmjam.github.io/resources/#sample-paper&quot;&gt;sample paper&lt;/a&gt; for an example of acceptable work.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't know how to cite your research? ASK! M&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;J's Discord is a great place to get quick help from event runners and your math modeling community.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Academic honesty is the principle of being honest in all the work you do. In the context of M3J, an academically honest team creates their own model and reports it without cheating or presenting the work of others as their own. If academic dishonesty is detected, teams will be given a 2-hour window to correct their mistake. Otherwise, the M3J Team will disqualify the paper to ensure a fair playing field for everyone. Research is encouraged and an important part of making a good model. If you ever quote, paraphrase, use an image or graph that you did not make, or reference facts that you found while researching, you MUST cite your sources. You cannot take credit for work that is not yours. For example, below is a acceptable citation for this webpage that was generated through Easybib: Team, MMMJ. &quot;MMMJ Website.&quot; M3J, 1 Jan. 2021, mmmjam.github.io/. Refer to the sample paper for an example of acceptable work. Don't know how to cite your research? ASK! M3J's Discord is a great place to get quick help from event runners and your math modeling community.</summary></entry></feed>